If it's in a word, or it's in a look, you can't get rid of...
The Babadook is a drama, horror film directed by Jennifer Kent.
A single mother, plagued by the violent death of her husband, battles with her son's fear of a
monster lurking in the house, but soon discovers a sinister presence all around her.
Amelia Vanek, played by Essie Davis.
Samuel Vanek, played by Noah Wiseman.
Claire, played by Hayley McElhinney.
Robbie, played by Daniel Henshall.
Gracie Roach, played by Barbara West.
Oskar Vanek, played by Ben Winspear.
The Babadook is a 2014 Australian psychological horror film written and directed by Jennifer
Kent in her feature directorial debut, based on her 2005 short film Monster.
Starring Essie Davis, Noah Wiseman, Daniel Henshall, Hayley McElhinney, Barbara West, and Ben Winspear, the film follows
a widowed single mother who, with her son, must confront a mysterious humanoid monster in their home.
Kent began writing the screenplay in 2009, intending to
explore parenting, grief, and the fear of madness.
Financing was secured through Australian government
grants and partly through crowdfunding.
Filming took place in Adelaide, where Kent drew from her experiences as a
production assistant on Lars von Trier's Dogville (2003).
During filming, the production team worked to ensure six-year-old Wiseman
was protected from the film's disturbing subject matter.
The Babadook premiered at the Sundance Film Festival on 17 January 2014 and was given a limited release in
Australian cinemas on 22 May 2014, initially failing to become a commercial success in its native country.
However, it generated wider attention internationally,
grossing $10 million against its $2 million budget.
The film was praised for the cast's performances,
creature design, premise, and themes.
At the 4th AACTA Awards, it won for Best Film, and Kent won for Best
Direction and Best Original Screenplay, respectively.
In the years since its release, The Babadook has become a cult classic.
The film explores themes of monster, nightmare, parent child
relationship, dysfunctional family, sleeplessness.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.